<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://adit.blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://adit.blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-26T10:47:21+07:00</updated><id>https://adit.blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aditia’s Blog</title><subtitle>The personal blog of Aditia.</subtitle><author><name>Aditia</name></author><entry><title type="html">My Startup Goal for 2021</title><link href="https://adit.blog/build%20in%20public/my-startup-goal-for-2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Startup Goal for 2021" /><published>2021-06-19T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2021-06-19T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>https://adit.blog/build%20in%20public/my-startup-goal-for-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://adit.blog/build%20in%20public/my-startup-goal-for-2021/">&lt;p&gt;Every indie makers out there like to post their goals in public. Partly for accountability, partly for self-motivation. Fine, I’ll post mine here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My startup goal for 2021 is &lt;strong&gt;$5 &lt;abbr title=&quot;Annual Recurring Revenue&quot;&gt;ARR&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you read that right–that’s not a typo. Five bucks a year. That’s my goal. In the age of hustle and conquer culture, who wants to set a low standard? Me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other people might set their goal to four or even five digits yearly recurring revenue for their startup. But I’m going to set it to $5. Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;optimizing-for-happiness&quot;&gt;Optimizing for happiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it true that unreasonable expectations lead to disappointments. Setting a low target would keep the pressure off my back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting an unreasonable target, on the other hand, would dread and haunt me. And when I couldn’t achieve it, I will be disappointed. I will think lowly of myself and worse, won’t trust myself for the next shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to take that path. I want to be happy and I have a better chance of being happy if I set a single-digit &lt;abbr title=&quot;Annual Recurring Revenue&quot;&gt;ARR&lt;/abbr&gt; instead of other lofty figures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sustainable&quot;&gt;Sustainable&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a startup is hard enough. You have to figure out the right tech stack—reading all those documentations, references, and reviews. All while having a day job and raising a family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to set boundaries here. Otherwise, my physical and mental well-being will be in jeopardy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a startup doesn’t have to make you suffer. We should enjoy the process because we’re here for the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting a low target means that I don’t have to live on the edge. I can take a break if I need to, spend quality times with my family, and keep my day job. No, thanks, I don’t want burnout, please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;to-sum-it-up&quot;&gt;To sum it up…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to see five internet dollars by the end of this year. That would be the right amount. That number has a good chance of making me happy and enjoy this startup ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you’re wondering what I’m building for my startup, stay tuned. I will write another post, soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Aditia</name></author><category term="[&quot;Build in Public&quot;]" /><category term="goal" /><category term="happiness" /><summary type="html">Every indie makers out there like to post their goals in public. Partly for accountability, partly for self-motivation. Fine, I'll post mine here.</summary></entry></feed>